<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<element name="Weiler's Ward" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic for 5th Edition" id="ID_KBP_DMF5E_SPELL_WEILERS_WARD">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create four small orbs of faerie magic that float around your head and give off dim light out to a radius of 15 feet. Whenever a Large or smaller enemy enters that area of dim light, or starts its turn in the area, you can use your reaction to attack it with one or more of the orbs. The enemy creature makes a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is pushed 20 feet directly away from you, and each orb you used in the attack explodes violently, dealing 1d6 force damage to the creature.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the number of orbs increases by one for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a lock of hair from a fey creature</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Writhing Arms" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic for 5th Edition" id="ID_KBP_DMF5E_SPELL_WRITHING_ARMS">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your arms become constantly writhing tentacles. You can use your action to make a melee spell attack against any target within range. The target takes 1d10 necrotic damage and is grappled (escape DC is your spell save DC).</p>
			<p>If the target does not escape your grapple, you can use your action on each subsequent turn to deal 1d10 necrotic damage to the target automatically.</p>
			<p>Although you control the tentacles, they make it difficult to manipulate items. You cannot wield weapons or hold objects, including material components, while under the effects of this spell.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage you deal with your tentacle attack increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords" />
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>